我能加入你们的创业公司吗？
Can I be part of your start-up?
为什么？
Why?
什么为什么？
Why. as in?
你们都是工程师
You all are engineers
需要一个MBA
You need an MBA
纳文来过电话
Naveen had called
尤吉和纳文已经辞职了
Yogi and Naveen have quit their jobs and...
正在计划开始创业
are planning a start up.
我觉得你应该加入他们
I feel you should join them
不管怎样，你得和爸爸谈谈这件事
Anyhow, you have to speak to dad regarding this
我真的很想参与进来
I really want to be part of this
除非你能解决他们的问题
Unless you don't solve one of their problems
否则他们就不需要你
they don't need you
我认识一个程序员，他三年级了
I know a coder, he is in 3rd year
让他加入吧，相信我，他会很棒的
Let's get him onboard. Trust me. He'll rock!
我研究过你的想法
I looked into your idea
是个好想法
It's quite interesting actually
但是，我还没有给你发邮件
But, I haven't mailed you anything yet
邮件隐私是个神话，朋友
Privacy on mail is a myth, my friend.
我想我们需要杰图
I think we need Jeetu
你觉得我们需要杰图吗？
You think we need jeetu?
我们需要杰图
We need Jeetu.
我不能参加了，对不起
I'll not be able to join. Sorry!
你为什么这么怕你爸爸？
Why are you so scared of your Dad?
我能解决你的问题
I can solve your problem
我可以给你你需要的东西
I can give you something which you need.
我可以给你杰图
I can give you Jeetu.
直到你找到第一笔投资
Untill you find an investment
由我来支付杰图的工资
I'll pay for Jeetu's salary
干杯
Cheers!
我们有四个人了
and then "There were Four".
好的！干杯！
Ok. Cheers! Cheers! Cheers!
要有勇气追随自己的心声和直觉，
它们在某种程度上知道你想成为的样子
你们的想法很好
Your idea is very good.
我要去美国
I am going to U.S
等我从美国回来
As soon as I am back from U.S
我们将启动投资程序
We will start the investment process
太好了
Great!...
好的
ok
真不错
That's..
哇.
wow..
那么，西山
So, zeeshan!
你什么时候回来？
When do you return?
我回到了2016年11月
I am back in november 2016
2016年11月 ？
November 2016..?
是啊，有事要忙
Yeah.. got some work
但是你们不用担心
But you guys don't worry
一旦我回来，我们就会完成投资并开始工作
A soon as I am back, we'll complete the funding and start the work
记住我说的
and mark my words
2030年第三季度
By quarter 3, 2030!
你将成为垂直行业的第一名
You will be number 1 in your verticle
2030年？
2030?
是的2030年
Yes.. 2030!
你必须理解风险投资者的思维
You have to understand and get into the mind of the VC
他们都是有钱人
they are all very rich guys
你们要穿得正式一点
you have to suit up a little bit
看起来更专业一点
You have to look a little professional
老板! 我觉得这都是胡说八道
Boss! I think all that is bullshit!
下次开会时穿 t 恤和拖鞋
Next time wear a t-shirt and slippers to meeting
把脚放在桌子上，告诉他
Keep your feet on the table and tell him
开张支票，不然我就走了
write a cheque, or else I am leaving moth*rf**ker
自信是关键
Confidence is the key!
因此，一旦获得足够的用户，我们就计划筹集第二轮资金
So, once we acquire enough users, we plan to raise a second round
我们甚至可能只做移动端，就像Flat-Chat!
We might even go mobile only. Just like Flat-Chat!
你觉得怎么样？
So, What do you think?
高拉夫
Gaurav!
哈恩
Haan!
好的，等一下
yes. One sec
你们都是2011年毕业的对吧？
Guys, you all are from 2011 batch. Right?
太好了
yes!
你们认识莎娜·奥贝罗伊吗？
Do you guys know Shaina Oberoi?
莎娜·奥贝罗伊？
Shaina Oberoi?
你们有她的电话吗？
Do you guys have her number?
没有吗？
No?
你们需要多少资金？
How much funding do you need?
你们在两年半的时间里把公司运营的很好
You have set it up well in two and a half years.
投资者非常看好外卖业务
Investors were very excited about the idea of delivering Indian food to homes
而且价格实惠
and its very affordable
你现在吃的这顿饭要花435块钱
The meal that you are eating now costs Rs. 435
太酷了，三份餐只要435
Cool. Rs.435 for 3 plates.
435块钱
Its Rs.435!
我有400
I have Rs.400
要自信，把你的脚放在桌子上
Be confident, place your foot on the table
我就给你资金
I'll give you the funding.
就现在
like Now!
专业一点
Be professional
给我点自信
Show me some Confidence!
你在想什么？
What are you thinking?
太好了
Yes!
这还差不多，老大
That's more like it. Boss!
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
你拿不到我的钱
You will not get my money and
我会保证不会有人给你融资
I will make sure no body funds you in Hiranandaani.
你不能把脚抬起来
You don't keep your foot up.
他会的，他为什么不呢？
He will. How will he not?
我在硅谷待了17年
I lived in the silicon valley for 17 years
我在那里投资了差不多5家公司
I have invested in like 5 companies there
但是在印度
But India
泥土的芬芳把我带到了这个国家
The fragrance of soil has dragged me to this country.
你知道，我想在印度做一些事情
You know, I want do something Indian
我们将打造印度的优步
we will make India's Uber
我们称之为印度步
We call it "Induber".
你懂我的意思了吧
You getting what Iam saying!
明白吗
you see..
为什么你的团队里没有女性？
Why don't you have any females in your team?
你认为女人和男人不同？
You think woman are not on par with men
我白手起家创办了佐波罗
I started Zorpolo from scratch
今天，市值五千万
and today, it's worth 50 f**king million
你们为什么没有女性联合创始人？
Why don't you have any female co-founders?
来和我一起唱，快点，怎么了？
Come on join me.. come on.. what's wrong?
唱起来
come on.. come on..
融资的过程就好似一场摩诃婆罗多之战
Getting a funding is equal to fighting the battle of Mahabharatha
虽然班度五子有五个人
Pandavas were 5 of them, though.
为了赢得这场战争，你们需要什么？
Now to win this war, what do you guys need?
激情
Passion
承诺
Commitment
和奉献精神
and Dedication
这是一个比喻
It was retorical
问问我们需要什么？
Ask what is needed?
需要什么，先生？
What is needed Sir?
我们需要什里·克里希纳（印度神话中足智多谋的英雄）
We need Shree Krishna!
告诉我，你们中间谁是阿俊？
Tell me, who is Arjun among you guys?
阿俊？
Arjun?
应该是杰图吧? 我应该是尤迪斯提尔
should be Jeetu? I can be Yudistir.
我从不说谎
No Iam Yudistir, I never lie
你是比姆? 不，我是比姆
You are Bheem? No.. Dibs on Bheem.
你是萨哈杰夫
You are Sehdev
你是比姆？
You are Bheem?
纳文，对，就是纳文
Naveen.. ya Naveen
是的，就我吧，我是阿俊
Ya..I think it's me. Iam Arjun.
你好，Arjun
Hello Arjun
啊
Ah..
1972年
In 1972
我父亲在比卡内尔的街上开了一家小店
my gradfather started a small bhujiya shop on the streets of Bikaner
一个小商店
a small shop
到了今天
and today
无论是早餐与喝茶或啤酒搭配小吃
Weather its breakfast with tea or snacks with beer
人们只认准我们的品牌，
it's only our brand, that people use
25年来，我们一直是市场的领导者
It's been 25 years, we are leading the market
我们还上了上个月《财富》杂志的封面
also we were on the cover page of last month's Fortune magazine.
尽管如此
Despite of all this
你知道人们在背后怎么称呼我们吗？
Do you know what people call us behind our back?
他们说你什么？
What do they say?
布吉亚瓦拉（臭名昭著的印度食品品牌）
Bhujiyawaala!
这就是你想扩张到不同领域的原因吗？
So that's why you want to expand to different sectors?
你越来越明白了
You are catching on..
我要把我的钱投资在新的冒险上
I am putting my money on new ventures
你们的产品很令人兴奋
Your product is very exciting
非常适合我们的多样化经营
Perfect for our diversification.
我想在你们身上投资
I want to invest in you guys
太好了，加里
That's great Gary
实际上我们想稀释15% 到20% 的股权
we actually wanted to dilute 15 to 20% of our equity
融资在120万到160万之间
for around 1.2 to 1.6
你们来决定金额
You guys decide the number
我来决定股权结构
I' ll decide the equity
我至少要51%
I want atleast 51%
但是先生，51% 的股份就等于你成了我们公司的老板
But sir 51% practically makes you the owner of the company
公司？
Company?
你是说... 你们四个？
You mean.. four of you?
哈？
haan?
如果你们有一个人生病了，就连桌麻将都凑不齐
If one falls sick, you won't be having a proper teams to play carrom
还公司呢
Company!
你们的市场价格
Amount that you're asking for in the market
乘以4
multiplied by 4
再加上我的品牌
plus my brand
我的人脉
My contacts
还有办公室
Plus new office space
这完全不是一笔坏交易
Its not a bad deal at all
先生，您能降低到30-35% 吗
Sir can we negotiate somewhere around 30-35%
我不是来买菜的，混蛋
I am not selling vegetables, you As*h*le
那个…… 加里，这是一个非常困难的决定
Ah! Gary, but this is a very difficult decision
我们会仔细考虑，然后告诉你
we will think over it and let you know
51% 已经很多了
like 51% is a lot
克里斯克先生曾经问过亲人阿俊
Shree Kriskna had asked Arjun, the blood of his own family members
我只是想要更多的股权
I am just asking for a little more stake
没其他的了
nothing much.
我们星期天再谈
Will talk about it on Sunday
帕斯
Parth.
帕斯？
Parth?
我叫纳文
Naveen.
帕斯
Parth!
对不起! 对不起! 对不起... 对不起
Sorry! Sorry! Sorry... Sorry.
不用，你自己走吧
No no.. Please.
走啊
Go on..
我不想拖你的后腿
I don't want to hold you back.
不，我在考虑加里的提议
No.. I was thinking about Gary's proposal..
纳文
Naveen!
你知道吗，我们现在差不多一周才见一次面
Do you realise we, meet like once a week now.
我去你家的时候你都很忙
You'll be busy when I come to your place
你就不能和我好好聊5分钟吗？
Can't you talk to me for 5 minutes properly?
对不起，对不起
I'm sorry. sorry!
你不觉得这些天你说对不起太频繁了吗？
Don't you think you have been saying sorry too often these days?
对不..
Iam sor....
是啊，最近我搞砸了很多事情
Yeah maybe I am screwing up a lot these days
我真的很抱歉
I am really sorry
纳文，这样不行
Naveen, Its not gonna work like this.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk..
对不起对不起
I am sorry.. I am sorry..
宝贝，你害怕了？
Aww Baby.. You got scared?
一点都不好笑
Arey. It's not funny.
尤吉说
Yogi was saying
艾什就是这么分手的
Ashish brokeup the same way
他忙于创业
He got busy with the startup
没时间陪女朋友
he couldn't give time to his girlfriend
胡说八道
What nonsense!
真是陈词滥调
such a cliche.
但是陈词滥调的存在是有原因的
But cliches exists for a reason
让我们来点刺激的？
Let us do some clihe?
我们去果阿吧
Let's go to Goa.
你的班加罗尔之旅怎么办？
What about your Bangalore trip?
我不去了
I'll skip it
而且我们甚至不知道这个周末后我们什么时候有时间
and moreover we dont even know when we get time after this weekend.
别犯傻了
Don't be foolish and
暂时忘掉工作吧
ignore the job.
在接下来的30年里，就算我不陪着你了，你的工作也会一直伴随着你
Your job stays with you for the next 30 years, even if I don't
去班加罗尔吧
just go to Bangalore
我们去果阿吧
Lets go to Goa!
It's just a small project, anyway
无论如何，这只是一个小项目
这是你的工作
Arey, its your work ya
不要欺骗你的工作
Don't cheat your work!
改天再去果阿
Will go to Goa someother time.
好啊，那你以什么身份去？
Ok. What defines you better?
麦肯锡的商业顾问还是纳文·班萨尔的女朋友？
Business Consultant at Mckenzie or Naveen Bansal's girlfirend?
告诉我
Tell me.
好吧
Ok fine.
我去班加罗尔
I will go to Bangalore
高兴了吧
Happy?
一点都不浪漫
Very unromantic as*hole
什么不浪漫啊
What un-romantic as*hole
我们在这里也可以玩得很开心
We can have fun here as well.
想喝点什么吗？
wanna drink something?
一份榛子卡普奇诺和一份鸡肉三明治
Ya.. One hazelnut cappucino and one Chicken tikka sandwich
请来一杯茶和两杯咖啡
One tea and two idlis please.
甜点呢？
and dessert?
你这有什么烟？
and what cigerrates do you have?
戈德弗雷克，先生
Goldflake. Sir
周三，我画出了第二幅 FD
I have drawn the second FD too on wednesday.
尤吉正在寻找贷款
Yogi is looking for loan
不知道还要依赖曼达尔多久
and don't know how much to depend on Mandal!
关于加里的提议
and about Gary's proposal
有时觉得这是必须的
at times feel it's a necessity
有时我又觉得很贪婪
and some times I feel its greed!
但是你不一定要满足于加里
But you don't have to necessarily settle for Gary
明天你有个活动
Tomorrow, you have an event
不会有潜在的投资者吗？
won't there be potential investors?
会有... 但是..
there will be.. But..
也许这是最后一次了
may be for one last time.
我们没时间了，史瑞雅
We are running out of time, Shreya
如果没有一个投资者对我们明天的展示感兴趣
If none of the investors show any interest in our tommorow's presentation
我们可能只有加里这一条路了
we might have to go with Gary
你有没有试过庭审的方法？
Did you try your Jury room approach?
不，还没有
No.. not yet.
你的三个合伙人怎么说？
What do your 3 stooges say?
目前都还没有说什么
Nothing as yet
他们指望我做出正确的决定
They are banking on me to take the right decision.
这让我更害怕了
That's getting me more scared
我现在就可以拥抱你
I could hug you right now
说你会成功的
and say that you will be great
你会做出正确的决定
you will make the right decision
或者
or
我可以不那么夸张地告诉你
I could be less dramatic and tell you
我相信你 纳文巴萨尔
I believe in you Naveen Bansal
和在家里等你的那三个男孩一样
Just like the 3 boys waiting for you at home.
哦，该死
Oh Shit!
发生了什么？
What happened?
等等，等等，我能打包吗? 6个点心，2杯茶..
wait.. wait.. can I get a parcel..? 6 idli's, 2 chai...
先生，我收摊了
Sir. Food got over.
他怎么还不回来？
Where is he still?
他说他15分钟后回来，现在已经两个小时了
He said he will return in 15 minutes, its been 2 hours now.
叫我等一下喝杯茶
asked me to wait just for a tea.
我得回家睡觉了
I need to go home and sleep
尤基，现在就给他打电话
Yogi, call him now.
他把手机落在这儿了
He left his phone here
我们可以在这里自己泡茶
we would have made tea here itself
如果这个沙雕没有把所有的牛奶来凝乳
If this as*hole wouldn't have used all the milk to set the curd
明天是个重要的日子
Tomorrow is an important day
如果我们不吃凝乳和糖，我们怎么会走运呢？
How do we get lucky if we don't eat curd and sugar?
闭嘴! 你这个废物
Shut up! You piece of crap
沙雕
As*hole
在过去的6个小时里，你唯一的作用就是更改了谢谢的字体
For the last 6 hours you are only changing the font of Thank You.
留下一个持久的印象是很重要的
Aey.. Aey.. Its very important to make a lasting impression. Ok!
至少我早上起来没去城里闲逛
Atleast I am not roaming around the city since morning
我去印名片了，你这个混蛋
I had been to print visiting cards, you motherf*ckr
当你和投资者见面时，他们要求联系你，你会怎么做？
What do you do when you meet investors and they ask for contacts?
伙计们，这是怎么回事？
Guys, what's happening here?
纳文， 这是办公室骚扰
Naveen, this is harrasement at work place
我不能这样工作
I can't work like this.
我不能容忍这种事
I can't tolerate this.
你不能忍受什么？
What you can't tolerate?
你会把我的笔记本电脑带到房间然后看着华尔街之狼打飞机
You 'll take my laptop to the room and jerk off watching Wolf of Wallstreet
不，我是在准备演讲
No, I was preparing for the pitch.
老子搞死你
I''ll kill you ba*t**d
你知道我在触摸板上看到了什么吗？
You know what I saw on touchpad?
尤吉，你在说什么？
Yogi, what are you saying man?
我们都用上了消毒剂，杰图你跟他说
We had to use sanitizer, Jeetu tell him.
别这样，尤吉
Stop it.. Stop it Yogi.
尤吉，注意你的年龄
Yogi, Behave your age.
你从10年级开始就在欺负我们
You are bullying us since 10th standard.
别说了
Stop it now.
曼达尔，他说得对，那天触摸板上有东西
Madal, he's right. there's was something on the touchpad that day!
杰图! 你在怀疑我吗？
Jeetu! You are doubting me?
我发誓，那只是凝乳
I swear, it was just curd.
杰图 放松
Jeetu relax
我们明天有活动，别紧张
we have an event tomorrow, don't be stressed.
你安静点
You be quiet.
你知道什么是压力吗？
Do you even know what stress is?
桑亚三天之前想吃西瓜
Soumya is asking for watermelon from past 3 days
我不能买给她是因为
and I am not able to do it because
过去两天我都在处理一个编译错误
from past 2 days I am getting a compilation error
我已经在这里待两天了，已经筋疲力尽了
I am lying here since 2 days and I am exhausted doing this
我想今天好好睡一觉，为明天的活动做好准备
I thought of having a good sleep today to be ready for tomorrow's event
但现在你迟到了两个小时，把一切都毁了
But now you ruined it by coming two hours late
现在包里瓦利市场早上6点开市
Now, the market at Borivali opens at 6am
我得去那里买
I have to buy it from there.
桑亚还要叫我去买新鲜的鱼
Soumya will also ask me to get fresh fish also
所以我需要一手拿着西瓜，一手拿着鱼
So I need to carry watermelon in one hand and fish in the other
然后从包里瓦利坐火车
and travel in local train from Borivilli
因为我的自行车轮胎被扎破了
because my bike is punctured and
我没有时间去修，因为我已经待在这里两天了
no time to repair it because I am lying here since the last two days
强调一下
Stress it seems.
接一下
Hold this!
早餐准备好了吗？
Is breakfast ready?
麻烦快一点
Set it up quickly, please!
你看到我的信息了吗？
Did you read my message?
我还没时间看
I don't have time now
我已经迟到半小时了
I am already runing late by half an hour
我得收拾一下赶紧走了
I have to get fresh and leave.
星期天早上你要去哪儿，孩子？
Where are you going on Sunday morning, son?
爸爸
Dad!
不是的，我侄子说
Arey No.. my nephew was saying
维斯瓦纳坦 · 阿南德根本不喜欢油炸伊德利
Vishwanathan Anand doesn't like fried idli at all
什么？
What?
说真的
Ya seriously
人太多了
Too much crowd..
这些二十四五岁的孩子一毕业就想开公司
These 24-25 years kids try to start the company as soon as they get out of college.
他们中的一半甚至可能都不知道企业家怎么拼写
Half of them might not even know the spelling of entreprenuer
都是弟弟
All virgin as*es!
那个女孩看起来比较小
That qeue looks smaller.
这里是在排队签到吗？
Is this the line for Registration?
不
No!
我们在这等着领通行证
We are standing to pick up the ration
哈哈哈
hahaha
一帮沙雕
As*hole
你认识他吗？
Do you know him?
谁？
whom?
他叫阿米特·阿瓦斯蒂，那家伙想成为扎克伯格
That guy. Wanna be Zukerburg, Amit Awasti.
在哈莫尔布尔计算机学院拿到的工学学位
completed his B-Tech from NIT Hamirpur
却穿着哈沃德T恤炫耀
but wears Harward T-shit to show-off
他是"诉讼律师"的创始人
He is the founder of Litigator
诉讼律师？
Litigator?
一个律师的社交网络app
Its the social network for Lawyers.
去年3月，他们与联合创始人就股权问题发生了争执
They had issues with co-founder regarding equity last March
他们用他自己的应用程序对他提起诉讼
They used his own app to file a lawsuit against him
你认识他吗？
Do you recognise him?
谁? 囧雪？
who? John Snow?
什么雪？
who Snow?
那个穿黑西装的家伙？
That guy in black suit?
黑西装
Oh..the guy in black suit?
对
Ya.
嗯
haan.
不认识
No.
他是送奶网站的创始人 里特维克·穆赫吉
He is the founder of milkman.com, Ritwik mukherjee.
哦哦
Okay.
送奶工我听说过它就像乳制品的优步
Milkman. I've heard about it. Its like the Uber of dairy products
乳制品个屁
Dairy products my ass !
那是一个在线马厩
Its just an online stable.
2012年，它的名字是 dudhwala. com..
In 2012, it started of with the name dudhwala.com...
但后来政府以为它是色情网站，就禁止了它
but then government banned it thinking it's a porn website.
现在他们用一个新的名字重新启动了它
Now they have relaunched it with a new name.
顺便说一下，我是索拉布 · 曼达尔
By the way, I'm Saurabh Mandal.
这是纳文 巴萨尔
This is Naveen Bansal
还有尤吉
And yogi.
你好，先生
Hello sir.
你有 VC 吗？
Do you have a VC ?
名片？
Visiting card ?
有有有，刚印好的
Yes, I do. Freshly baked .
那就交换一下吧
Then give it.
事实上，在这样的场合中你会遇到很多欺诈行为
Actually you meet a lot of frauds in such events.
上次有个混蛋拍了一张自拍，说“我是拉胡尔 · 亚达夫”
Last time some asshole clicked a selfie saying "I am Rahul Yadav".
后来我才知道那个混蛋是个学生
Later I got to know that asshole was just a B.com student from Mithibhai.
用两只手递名片，一只手不礼貌
Give it using two hands... With one hand is cnsidered unluncky!
我们都是同龄人，这些应该不用我告诉你的
You should be knowing all of this, we are of same age.
拿着
Take it.
对，就像这样
ya.. like that
拉维 · 拉斯托吉
Ravi Ram Rastogi.
嗯
Hmm..
首席执行官、首席技术官、首席营销官
CEO, CTO, CMO
Superentreprenuer.com 创始人
Founder, Superentreprenuer.com
这是我的第八家公司
This is my 8th company
在这之前的那七家呢？
and about those seven before this?
都倒闭了
They were shut down.
哦
Oh!
但是这一次我将进入财富500强
But this one will take me to the list of Fortune 500
等着瞧吧
Wait and Watch!
事情是... 听好了
Thing is.. Hello..
事情是这样的
So the thing is
企业家的灵魂总是不安分的
The soul of entreprenuer is always restless.
它会一直游荡，直到你想出一个杰作
It will roaming around untill you come up with a masterpiece.
这么说只有你们三个？
So only 3 of you guys?
不，先生
No sir..
不，不，很好
No.. no. Its good.
联合创始人数量越少，股权价值就越高
The lesser number of co-founders, higher will be the equity value.
不，先生，我们有四个人，杰图正在来的路上
No sir, we are four of us. Jeetu is on his way
尤吉，打电话问他在哪里？
Yogi, call him and ask where did he reach?
好吧 那就是8% 的损失
Oho.. that's like 8% loss.
没问题，继续
No problem, carry on!
算了吧，爸爸
Leave it Dad.
在保修期内
It's in the warranty
公司的人会免费来修的
company guy will come and fix it for free.
你学的是计算机科学而不是机械
haan. You studied computer science instead of mechanical
你可能会厌倦做这些事情
you might get tired to do all these stuffs
给我一个更大的螺丝刀？
give me a bigger screw driver?
尤吉：你在哪里
你手机里有螺丝刀吗？
are you looking for app for it?
不，不，是关于工作的
No.. no. Its about work
瓦钦说
Watchen was saying..
你两天没回家了
You didn't come home for 2 days.
是这样的，爸爸
Actually Dad.
公司的人让他加班
the company guys are making him work a lot
因为这个项目
beacuse of the project
他们每天都给他打电话，星期天都不让休息
they call him daily, even on sundays
你去收拾一下
You get fresh
准备好
get ready
爸爸，你想吃西瓜吗？
Dad, would you want to eat watermelon?
你们星期天有什么项目？
What kind of project do you have on Sunday's?
打电话告诉你老板
Call your boss and tell
你爸爸从比卡内尔来看你，所以今天不能加班
your dad has come from Bikaner, so can't come today.
把电话给我，让我跟你老板说
give the phone, let me speak to him
爸爸，事情不是这样的
Dad, It doesn't work that way.
我只待一天
have just come for a day
如果不是为了潘迪亚吉女儿的婚礼
If not for Pandyaji's daughter wedding
我才不来
I wouldn't have come.
你就不能和你爸爸吃个午饭吗
Can't you have lunch with your dad for a day
没有你，你的公司不会倒闭的
your company won't shut down without you.
现在翅膀这么硬了吗
Yu have grown up now right!
不是那样的，爸爸
nothing like that Dad.
我马上回来
I will just be back.
嘿! 我在跟你说话呢
Hey! I am talking to you!
给你老板回复一句等会再说
Send TTYL to your boss
爸爸
Dad
西瓜
Watermelon
喂，尤吉
Hello Yogi.
尤吉，我不能去了
Yogi i can't come
我爸突然来我家了
All of a sudden dad showed up!
什么?
What nonsense?!
是的! 他不让我走
yes! He is not allowing me to leave.
不让走？
Not allowing to leave?
你是四年级学生吗？
Are you a 4th grader?
唉……尤吉
Arey Yogi.
杰图？
Jeetu?
好的，爸爸，我来了
Yes dad i am coming.
我在说重要的事，你却在撒尿?
I am talking something important, and you are peeing?!
等等吧，尤吉
Just wait Yogi.
杰图？
Jeetu?
研讨会快结束了，午餐后的活动很关键
The seminar is about end, post lunch is our main event.
快点过来
Leave quickly!
尤吉，我一会儿再和你谈
Yogi I will talk to you later
杰图？
Jeetu?
是的，爸爸
yes dad!
这是什么？
What is this?
看起来像一条内裤
looks like a boxer
它卡在水箱后面了
it was stuck behind the tank
你都没有时间检查下洗了多少衣服吗
You don't even have time to keep your clothes in check.
你在洗手间干什么？
and what were you doimg in the bathroom?
没什么，电话..
nothing.. phone...
我在小便
I was peeing.
小便之后你要洗手
you will wash your hands after that or
不然公司的人都会开始不洗手
anyone from the company will come to do it.
真的非常抱歉，但这是我第四次告诉您
I'm really really sorry sir, but this is the fourth time i'm telling you
除非团队人到齐了，否则我不能给你们通行证
that i can not give you the passes until the entire team registered
但是你总得让我们创业啊
But madam you have to let us startup
这是我们的名片
This is our VC card
对不起，先生，我们必须遵守一些规定
I am sorry sir. We have to follow certain guidelines.
听着
See, listen...
阿普尔瓦
Apoorva..
阿普尔瓦，我们的朋友在路上了
Apoorva, our friend is on his way.
难道不能先给我们三张通行证吗
Isn't it possible to first give us our three passes.
朋友的通行证等他到了你再给他
Like, you can hold on to our friend's pass.
他到的时候来找你拿
He will collect it from you, when he is here.
让我看看
Let me check.
纳文
Naveen.
纳文……
Naveen..
其实我
Actually I
刚刚发现..
just found out that...
这里不是电影院
this is not a movie theatre...
我们不能帮忙保管通行证
and we cannot hold on to your passes.
但是我们已经付了注册费..
But we have paid the registration fee....
每人1857卢比
1,857 Rupees per head.
先生，麻烦你靠边站
Sir, you're holding the que, could you please step aside.
你不能这样对我们..
You can't do this to us...
你找你领导出来
I want to speak to the management.
她怎么能这样跟我们说话？
How can she talk to us like this ?
我会让你被炒鱿鱼的
I'll get you fired.
记住我的话
Mark my words.
战斗才刚刚开始
The battle has just begun.
一场1857卢比的战争
The battle of 1,857 rupees.
诸神不会放过她的
Mangal and Pandey wont let her be.
别说了
Stop it.
什么人啊
What rubbish !
她怎么能这样跟我们说话
How can she talk to us like this.
放松
Relax.
让我们想想办法
Let's figure out something.
还有什么办法？
Figure out what?
她有每个人的档案
She has everyone's profiles.
杰图不来我们就进不去
We won't get entry without jitu
早就说了，走之前我们应该吃点糖和豆腐吧
I told you, let's have sugar and curd before leaving.
曼达尔，你快别bb了
Mandal, Please don't start again.
不要回答
Dont' answer.
回答
Answer.
嗨，加里
Hi Gary..
加里，我现在有点忙，过会儿我再打电话给你行吗？
Gary, I am little busy, can I call you after sometime ?
演讲还没开始呢
There's still time for the presentation to start, Parth..
你就已经开始忙了？
You're already busy ?
不是，我没有，加里
No Gary.
我们只是来看朋友的
We just came here to see a friend.
在这种场合不会遇到朋友
One doesn't meet friends in such events...
你要么遇到竞争对手，要么遇到投资者
You either meet your competition or investors!
别把我当傻瓜
Don't think of me as an idiot.
听着
And Listen..
你把免提打开
Put your phone on loudspeaker
这样你就不用比划了
Then you won't have to play Dumb charades.
好
Ya.
我没有生气..
I'm not upset...
如果我是你，我也会这么做的
If I was in your place I would have done the same.
你应该为你们的产品争取一个好价钱
You should get a good value for a good product..
没有比这更好的地方来实现你的产品价值了
and there is no better place then such events to realize your product's value.
加里，这是个好活动，但是我们..
Gary, It is a good event but we're.....
赶时间? 我知道
In a hurry ? I know..
你得见很多投资者..
You have to meet a lot of investors...
讨论一下你们的未来计划
have to discuss you're future plans
我知道
I know..
但在那之前，你不想听听我的新提议吗？
But before that, you dont want to listen to my new offer ?
新的提议？
New offer ?
我想了很多
I thought a lot..
然后我意识到这笔交易对你们有点不公平
Then I realised that this deal is little unfair for you..
所以我们这样，在你们的报价后面……
So the amount which you guys had proposed?
加一个零
Suffix a zero to the number.
加里
Gary..
那可是一大笔钱
That's a lot of money!
没错
No.
你想要很多钱..
You wanted a lot of money...
我现在就给你钱，十倍哦
and I am giving you a lot of money X 10
但是当然..
But ofcourse...
股本将是相同的... 51%
Equity will be the same... 51%.
这没有商量的余地
That is non-negotiable.
我正要去我的罗纳瓦拉农舍
I'm on my way to my lonavala farmhouse...
参加会议
For a meeting.
在我到达之前给我你的答案..
Give me your answer before I get there...
否则交易取消
Or the offer stands cancelled.
另外……
And ya...
如果你在那之前找到投资者的话……
If you get an investor before that then..
祝你一切顺利
All the best.
但是加里，我怎么能这么快回复你呢
But Gary how will I reply so fast
纳文，你是啤酒
Naveen you're beer
而我是蛇
And I am snakcs!
如果我们两个聚在一起，会很热闹的
If we both get together, we'll have a party!
我会等你的电话..
I'll be waiting for your call...
帕斯
Parth.
他刚才是不是给我们……
Did he just offer us...
在这样的关键时刻，杰图总是不见踪影
Jitu always goes missing in such crucial times.
曼达尔再给他发一次短信-好的
Mandal just text him once. -okay.
你怎么想
What are you thinking ?
我需要一个陪审室
I need a jury room.
闻起来真香
Smells nice!
你加味精了吗？
Have you added ajwaine?
是的，爸爸
Yes papa.
海鱼有一种很独特的味道
Salt water fish have a very unique taste..
很柔软
They're very soft soft.
是啊
ya.
我们那就吃不到
We don't get it over at our place!
加里提出10倍价格收购我们的项目，他要马上给答复，给我回电话快点
我两分钟后回来
I'll be back in two minutes.
吃着饭呢你要去哪里？
Where are you going at lunch time ?
就在附近买点牛奶... 楼下
Just closeby to get some milk... Rgiht below the building!
送牛奶的早上已经来了
The milkman has already come in the morning!
爸爸，我想我晚上会给你准备一些拉比
Dad. I though I'll prepare some 'Rabdi' for you in the evening!
牛奶少了，所以我让他去买
There was less milk so I asked him to.
是的，她让我这么做的
Ya she asked me to.
但是你为什么要在这么热的天气里出去呢？
But why do you need to go in this heat???
我下次会吃的
I will have it next time.
不，爸爸，不麻烦，我坚持
No Dad. It's no trouble. I insist.
桑娅做的腊肠很好吃，我2分钟就回来
Saumya makes nice 'rabdi'. I'll go get it in 2.
等一下，杰图
Wait a minute Jitu.
回来坐下
Sit over here.
闺女过来
Beta (daughter) listen.
去把这药给我煎了
Make me this concoction.
爸爸，我可以在午饭后去吗？
Papa, can I make it after lunch ?
不行，医生让我午饭时吃
No, the doctor has asked me to have it with lunch.
听好了
And listen.
慢慢来，慢慢煮
Take your time and boil it for long!
不用着急
There's no hurry.
好的，爸爸
Yes, Papa.
老实告诉我
Tell me honestly.
你要去哪里
Where were you going.
爸爸，去买牛奶，还有什么
Papa, to buy milk, whatelse.
你是要去抽烟吧
You were going to smoke a ciggarette.
爸爸，我在大学里就戒烟了
Papa, I quit smoking in college.
不要撒谎
Don't lie.
我在你公文包里找到了几根烟
I've found a few in your office bag!
爸爸
Papa..
我还要为你撒多少谎？
How much should I lie for you ?
在你结婚前..
Before marriage...
结婚前，我不得不对帕瑞玛撒谎说你不喝酒也不抽烟
Before marriage I had to lie to Parimal that you dont drink or smoke..
他们把女儿嫁到我们家是因为他们信任我们
They married their daughter into our family because they had trust in us.
你也答应过你妈妈
And you had promised your mom
你会戒烟
That you would quit smoking!
你戒了吗？
Did you quit?
好吧，对不起，爸爸
Okay, Sorry papa.
如果你真的想抽烟，那就嚼口香糖吧
If you get desperate to smoke than have a chewing gum .
哈迪亚尔就是这样戒烟的
Hardiyal quit it the same way.
好吧，爸爸，那我去楼下买点薄荷糖来
Okay Papa then I will go, get some mint from downstairs!
给你
Here.
拿去吧
Have it.
如果你再发出一点声音
If you make one more sound
我会把机油倒你嘴里让你漱口
I will put castrol in your mouth and make you gargle it.
我们还在等什么？
What are we waiting for ?
我们已经赚翻了
We are getting soo much money now!
如果我们继续拖时间，那这些钱就没了
If we take more time then even this plan will get ruined.
纳文有做决定的权利
Naveen has the first right to take a decision.
等他从陪审室出来
Let him come out of the jury room.
然后我们再做决定
Then we will decide.
这个陪审室是干什么的？
What is this jury room ?
我从大学时就看他这样做过
I've been sseing it since our college time.
每当纳文面对困境时
Whenever Naveen faces a dilema
他会把自己锁在房间里15分钟
He locks himself in a room for 15 minutes.
然后做出正确的决定
And he comes out with the right decision.
这就是为什么我们称之为陪审室
And thats why we call it a jury room.
但是在这种场合，他是怎么找到空房间的呢？
But in such a busy event, how did he find a empty room ?
这是典型的性别歧视
This is the height of sexism.
难道他们根本就不想让女性企业家来吗？
What, were they not expecting female entreprenuers at all ?
男厕所开着，但女厕所却锁着
Gents washroom is open but the female washroom is locked!
在这样的比赛中你碰到很多这样的事情
You will get a lot of mcps in such events.
你知道吗
You know what..
甚至在我的名片上印的都是我兄弟的电话号码
Even in my visiting card I have given my brothers number.
你是怎么做到的？
And how did you ?
如果一百块能够说服英国人... ..
If one Gandhiji can convice lacks of britishers ...
为什么二百块不能说服保洁员
Why wouldn't a housekeeper get convinced with two!
你们还在这儿？
You guys are still here ?
是啊
Ya.
没回家？
Didn't go home?
你们公司的 CEO 在哪里？
Where is that CEO of your's ?
我们正在等他
Actually that's who we are waiting for!
如果你有时间的话
If you're wasting time...
那就在推特上关注我吧
Then follow me on twitter!
好啊
Ya ya..
我有198个粉丝
I have 198 followers.
如果你们两个都关注我，那么那就破二百了
If you both follow me, then it'll become a double century.
妈的
Shit !
我只有116个粉..
I have only 116...
但是我在领英上有312个粉丝
But I have 312 followers on linkedIn.
312？
312 ?
妈的
Shit !
等我的应用程序发布
Just wait for my app to get launched..
看我怎么追上你
Then watch how I overtake you.
你为什么不去那边交朋友呢？
Why can't you go there and do your networking ?
其实我在等我的室友
Actually I am waiting for my roommate..
I forgot my keys.
我忘带钥匙了
其他七个人都被淘汰了
Even the other 7 are out.
他是来给我送钥匙的
So he is coming to give me the keys.
你们是9个人住在一起吗？
You'll are 9 people staying together?
四居室？
4 BHK ?
不不
No No..
两居室
It's a 2 BHK
但空间足够大
But spacious enough.
74平
800 sqft.
其实
Actually
自从我2008年离婚后..
Since I got a divorced in 2008...
我就不得不住在合租房里
I've to live in a shared apartment!
这样可以建立
It helps you build..
团队精神
Teamspirit.
你离婚了？
You had a divorce ?
是的
Yes.
对不起
Sorry.
你为什么说对不起？
Why you're saying sorry ?
当她不说对不起的时候
When she is not saying sorry..
你为什么说对不起？
Why you're saying sorry ?
没关系
It's okay.
并不是每个人的婚姻都那么完美
Everyone is not that lucky to have a Sudhamurthi in their life.
等我的公司拿到融资
Once my company gets funded...
老子一天换一个女朋友
Just wait and watch how 'Manglik' girls line up for me!
但是这么多年来，你一次融资也没拿到？
But in so many years you didn't get funded even once ?
也不是……
I did..
2003年的时候
In 2003 I did..
有一个投资者准备投我
There was an investor who was ready to invest..
但是要求50% 的股权
But was asking for 50% equity.
但是我们的创始人兼首席执行官
And our founder and CEO
有点像佛祖
Was sort of a buddha type..
他拒绝了
Said no to it .
从那以后直到今天... 我向上帝发誓
Since then till today... I swear to god
我唯一一次睡安稳觉的时候是在火车的卧铺车厢里
The only time I have slept peacefully is while travelling in a train's sleeper class.
喂
Ya karunesh..
Yes.
是的
进来吧
Come inside.
什么
What !
他们不让你进？
They aren't letting you?
你为什么总是穿短裤出门？
Why do you always come in boxers???
笨蛋
Dumbfuck!
怎么了？
What happened ?
说话啊？
Tell me what happened ?
尤吉？
Yogi ?
我已经决定了
Okay, I have decided.
什么？
What ?
我想等人齐了再说，我们一起去杰图家吧
I want to tell you'll with Jeetu. Let's go to his place .
你在干什么？
What are you doing ?
尤吉给我发短信了，我得下去一趟
Yogi'd texted me. I am going down.
他们在停车场等我
They are waiting for me in the parking lot.
如果爸爸醒了，我该怎么办？
What will I answer dad if he gets up ?
拖2分钟就好
Please handle it for 2mins..
求你了
Please..
Please.
好吧，你去吧
Okay, you go...
我拖住他
I will handle it.
他家三楼还是四楼？
Third floor or fourth floor ?
来了
Terrace !
别在这站着...-嘿，杰图
Don't stand... -Hey jitu, hie..
不要站在这里，这里的保安是我爸爸的间谍
Don't stand over here, the watchman out here is my dad's spy.
- 你怎么决定的?-曼达尔，把声音调小点
Hmm, so what did you decide? Mandal, lower the volume.
你怎么决定的，我们拿加里的钱，对吧？
So what did you decide, we are taking money from Gary, right ?
这家伙什么都没告诉我们
This one's not telling us anything at all!
不，我们不拿他的钱
No, we aren't taking money from Gary.
事实上我已经给他发短信说”不”了
Infact I already texted him saying "No".
纳文，这个决定背后的逻辑是什么？
Naveen, what is the logic behind this ?
什么逻辑，这是我们的想法，我们的努力
What logic, It's our idea our hardwork
我们花了这么长的时间来研究它
We are working on it from such a long time
现在怎么可以随意的把一半股权给别人？
Now randomly we would give away half the stakes to somebody, why ?
他给我们钱啊，这就是为什么，你还不明白吗
He is giving us money, that's why, don't you get it..
这对我们公司的估值有很大帮助啊
How it helps our compnay's valuation!
我向你保证，在一年内我们能创造更多的价值
I guarantee you, in one year we will create more value than this .
纳文
Naveen..
你是认真的吗
Are you serious !
我们甚至都不能参加今天的活动了
We couldn't even go for today's event
别想募集资金了
Forget about raising funds...
投资者绝不会打电话给我们第二次机会
Investors aren't calling us for even a second meeting.
你认为金主爸爸们会来……
You think Sikoya and Nexus will join hands...
求你接受他们的投资吗
and beg you to take their investments ? !
We'lll have to compromise a little, Naveen .
我们得妥协一下，纳文
你们难道没有意识到这个家伙是一个卑鄙的商人
Aren't you all realising that thios guy is a 'Bhujiyawaala'.
他甚至没有技术背景
He doesn't even have a technical background..
他将会如何理解我们的产品？
How will he understand our product ?
这是优势啊
That's the advantage.
如果他没有任何技术背景
If he doesn't have any technical knowledge
他就不会干涉的-如果他干涉呢？
he won't interfere . -what if he interferes ?
那我们就完了
Then we're fucked.
我们以后再考虑这个问题
We'll think about it later..
你怎么能独自做出如此重要的决定呢？
And how can you take such an important decision by yourself?
就因为你的名片上写着总裁
Just because you've C.E.O. on your visiting card...
并不意味着你就是老板
... doesn't mean you are the boss.
纳文
Naveen
我们是一个团队
We are a team..
但是团队里没有我
And there is no I in team.
兄弟们，不是这样的
Guys it isn't that..
每次我在陪审室里做出决定都是正确的
You know, whenever I've taken a decision in the jury room, it's always been right
是吗？
yes？
你在陪审室里到底是怎么做的？
And what exactly do you do in the jury room ?
什么？
What ?
我在问你
I am asking you!
你在陪审室里是怎么做决定的？
How do you take your decision in the jury room?
这很简单
It's simple..
He must be listing down the pros and cons..
他一定是在列举利弊
对其进行 SWAT 分析并确定可行性
Does a SWAT analysis of it and determines the probablity.
我在高中的时候也这样做过
Even I have done that in the third semester of my high school
SWAT分析？
SWAT analysis ?..
可行性？
Probablity ?..
他他妈的扔了一枚硬币然后就定了
He fucking tosses a coin and decides.
什么
What !
就这样？
Tosses and decides ?
纳文，看着我
Naveen look here..
当年我娶桑亚的时候就是让你做的决定啊！！
I had decided to marry saumya after asking you!
我不需要掷硬币来决定
I didn't need to toss a coin for that.
但是你今天就需要？
But you needed it today?
你他妈的用硬币决定了
You fucking decided four peoples carrer,ambition
四个人的事业，野心和未来！
and their future on the basis of tossing a coin !
如果是硬币的另一面呢？
And what if it was the other side of the coin ?
那么我们现在是不是应该在加里的农舍拍他马屁?
Then right now we would have been in Gary's farmhouse licking his ass ? !
纳文，你要下地狱我都跟你，但我不能跟随1卢比的硬币
Naveen I can follow you till hell but I can't follow a 1 Rupee coin.
纳文我们都辞职了
Naveen, everyone has left their job...
这家创业公司是你的主意，对吧？
This startup was your idea, right ?
我们在你家每天连续工作16个小时
We are working 16 hrs continously at your home.
然而这位首席执行官掷硬币做决定
And this CEO tosses a coin and decides.
至少你可以问我们一次？
Atleast you could have asked us once ?
这对你来说很难吗
Was that asking for too much from you?
你投出来的是什么? 正面还是反面?-我不知道
What was it Naveen? Head or tail ? - Guys I don't know what it was!
作出决定依据是抛硬币的过程，而不是抛硬币的结果
Decision was taken on the basis of tossing the coin, not on the result of it.
什么意思？
What do you mean ?
就像这枚硬币，生活给了我们两个选择..
Like this coin even life gives us 2 choices...
不管你列出多少赞成和反对的理由，双方的几率一定是平等的
No matter how many lists of pros and cons you make both sides would always be equal
而且你无法做出选择
And you won't be able to pick any side.
这时你能做的就是倾听你的心声
That time all you can do is listen to your heart.
这就是为什么如果你只抛一次硬币，你就会知道哪一面朝上
That's why if you toss the coin once, you will come to know which side won.
但是你还没看到它是正还是反？
But you didn't even see if it was a head or a tail ?
我不用看，已经听到了
I didnt see it but I heard it.
当硬币在空中的时候
When the coin stays in the air for half a second..
一个声音从你的心底传来……
A voice answers from the bottom of your heart...
说道：
Which says..
是正面，是正面
Please let it be heads, please heads!
这时你就会意识到不管硬币是正面还是反面
That's when you realize no matter what the result is...
你的内心希望它是正面的
Your heart wants it to be heads.
我意识到我们的第一笔投资不能建立在贪婪的基础上
And I have realised that our first investment can't be set on the basis of greed.
加里贪图公平，而我们贪图钱财
Where gary is in greed of equity and we of money
我们的第一笔投资应该是基于我们的..
Our first investment should be only on the basis of our...
创意与技术
Idea and skill.
如果只是因为钱，那我不能让任何人控制我的野心
Just for more funding I can't let anyone control my ambitions.
我真的很抱歉我不能这么做
I am really sorry I could'nt do it.
现在你们想怎么办
Now you guys decide what to do.
我们要去哪儿？
Where are we going ?
回去继续参加活动
Back to the event.
但是如果他们不让我们进去呢
But what if they don't let us in!
那就用我们的一贯操作
The same thing what we always do ..
试试
Try.
我们走
Let's go.